<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Probability on The Nightly Brew</title>
    <link>/categories/probability/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Probability on The Nightly Brew</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/probability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>False conviction rates for death sentences</title>
      <link>/2014/05/21/false-conviction-rates-for-death-sentences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/05/21/false-conviction-rates-for-death-sentences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine standing in a courtroom. You are the innocent defendant in a trial, being prosecuted for a terrible crime. The jury comes out and gives their verdict - your body goes numb. Guilty. You&amp;rsquo;re given a death sentence for a crime you didn&amp;rsquo;t commit. It&amp;rsquo;s a mind-boggling situation. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.law.umich.edu/special/exoneration/Documents/exonerations_us_1989_2012_full_report.pdf&#34;&gt;But it happens&lt;/a&gt;. We know it happens because we find people being exonerated from death sentences in light of new evidence, being released after half a lifetime in prison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hope is that this is a rare occurrence. But how often &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; it happen? &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birthday Paradox and Forensic Science</title>
      <link>/2014/05/19/birthday-paradox-and-forensic-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/05/19/birthday-paradox-and-forensic-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is derived from an interesting &lt;a href=&#34;http://lpr.oxfordjournals.org/content/12/1/3.full&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; found in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oxfordjournals.org/our_journals/lawprj/about.html&#34;&gt;Law, Probability, and Risk&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://scientopia.org/blogs/goodmath/2013/11/18/the-birthday-paradox/&#34;&gt;birthday paradox&lt;/a&gt;, which comes up in probability theory, is used in the paper. The paradox goes something like this: Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re in a classroom with 30 students, and you are asked how likely it is that any two of those students will have the same birthday (same month and day). Intuitively, it seems fairly unlikely to find two such students. After all, it&amp;rsquo;s uncommon that you as an individual will run into someone with your same birthday. But as it turns out&amp;hellip; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>